By Satan Possessed: The Search for the Devil is a
documentary film directed by Antony Thomas.
America Undercover looks at the phenomenon of Satanism in the World.
It talks to practitioners of Satan worship and interviews those
who claim that they have been victimized by it.
It also talks to some of the people who want to stamp Satanism out for good.
Same doc as 'In Satan’s Name', but with American narration.
Los Angeles Ritual Abuse Task Force, played by Catherine Gould.
Satan, also known as the Devil, is an entity in Abrahamic
religions who entices humans into sin or falsehood.
In Judaism, Satan is seen as an agent subservient to God, typically regarded
as a metaphor for the yetzer hara, or 'evil inclination'.
In Christianity and Islam, he is usually seen as a fallen angel or jinn who has rebelled against God,
who nevertheless allows him temporary power over the fallen world and a host of demons.
A figure known as ha-satan ("the satan") first appears in the Hebrew Bible as a heavenly prosecutor, subordinate to Yahweh
(God); he prosecutes the nation of Judah in the heavenly court and tests the loyalty of Yahweh's followers.
During the intertestamental period, possibly due to influence from the Zoroastrian figure of Angra Mainyu, the
satan developed into a malevolent entity with abhorrent qualities in dualistic opposition to God.
In the apocryphal Book of Jubilees, Yahweh grants the satan (referred to as Mastema) authority over a
group of fallen angels, or their offspring, to tempt humans to sin and punish them.
Although the Book of Genesis does not name him specifically, Christians
often identify the serpent in the Garden of Eden as Satan.
In the Synoptic Gospels, Satan tempts Jesus in the desert and is
identified as the cause of illness and temptation.
In the Book of Revelation, Satan appears as a Great Red Dragon, who is
defeated by Michael the Archangel and cast down from Heaven.
He is later bound for one thousand years, but is briefly set free before
being ultimately defeated and cast into the Lake of Fire.
In the Quran, Iblis (Shaitan), the leader of the devils (shayāṭīn), is made of fire and was
cast out of Heaven because he refused to bow before the newly created Adam.
He incites humans to sin by infecting their minds
with waswās ('evil suggestions').
In the Middle Ages, Satan played a minimal role in Christian theology
and was used as a comic relief figure in mystery plays.
During the early modern period, Satan's significance greatly increased as beliefs
such as demonic possession and witchcraft became more prevalent.
During the Age of Enlightenment, belief in the existence of Satan
was harshly criticized by thinkers such as Voltaire.
Nonetheless, belief in Satan has persisted, particularly in the Americas.
Although Satan is generally viewed as evil, some
groups have very different beliefs.
In theistic Satanism, Satan is considered a deity
who is either worshipped or revered.
In LaVeyan Satanism, Satan is a symbol of virtuous characteristics and liberty.
Satan's appearance is never described in the Bible, but, since the ninth century, he has often been shown in Christian
art with horns, cloven hooves, unusually hairy legs, and a tail, often naked and holding a pitchfork.
These are an amalgam of traits derived from various pagan
deities, including Pan, Poseidon, and Bes.
Satan appears frequently in Christian literature, most notably in Dante Alighieri's Inferno, all variants of the
classic Faust story, John Milton's Paradise Lost and Paradise Regained, and the poems of William Blake.
He continues to appear in literature, film, television, video game, and music.
The film explores themes of child abuse, heavy metal,
satanist, conspiracy theory, brainwashing.
The tone is lighthearted.